A Guide to the James Branch Cabell Collection, 1919-1938
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
James Branch Cabell Collection, 1919-1938
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5947-k
This collection consists of 27 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited on 1964 Jun 17.
Scope and Content Information
In this collection of letters, James Branch Cabell writes on literary subjects, discussing articles and reviews he has read and plans to write. Specifically, Cabell encourages De Casseres to read his Beyond Life and Jurgen and then thanks De Casseres for an article De Casseres subsequently wrote in support of Jurgen. In turn, Cabell compliments De Casseres' Muse of Lies and Shadow Eater. He expresses regret that his schedule does not permit him to write an introduction to the latter book. Two Christmas cards are included.
These letters are on microfilm(M-1367) and are in the order in which they are on the microfilm. Note: Original returned to Mr Cabell in 1964.
Contents List
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Benjamin De Casseres 1919 Nov 22, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1919 Dec 2, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1920 Jan 12, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1920 Apr 2, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1920 Jun 28, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1922 Aug 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1922 Dec 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1922 Dec 17, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1924 Mar 5, TLS. 1 p.
  [w/envelope]
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1925 Sep 9, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1925 Oct 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1926 Dec 1, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from Mr. and Mrs. J.B.C. to Mr. and Mrs. De Casseres n.d., Christmas card
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1928 Feb 16, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1928 Aug 29, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from Mr. and Mrs. J.B.C. to Mr. and Mrs. De Casseres [1926 Dec 29], Christmas card. [w/envelope]
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1929 Nov 5, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1930 Apr 10, TLS. [w/envelope, and 4 p. French enclosure] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1930 Sep 16, TLS. [w/envelope]. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1932 Jan 16, TLS. [w/envelope]. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1932 Jan 19, TLS. [w/envelope] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1932 Apr 2, TLS. [w/envelope] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1932 Apr 8, TLS. [w/envelope] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1934 Feb 27, TLS. [w/envelope]. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1936 Apr 24, TLS. [w/envelope] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1936 Aug 28, TLS. [w/envelope] 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to De Casseres 1938 Nov 4, TLS. [w/envelope] 1 p.